<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown on Byte Banter</title>
    <link>https://bytebanter.github.io/tags/markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Markdown on Byte Banter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>**[ByteBanter.com](https://www.bytebanter.com)**</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 21:06:56 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bytebanter.github.io/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://bytebanter.github.io/posts/0007-getting-started-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 21:06:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bytebanter.github.io/posts/0007-getting-started-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started with Hugo Hugo is a modern static website generator that can help you quickly create a website with a great user experience. It is a fast and powerful open source framework that is easy to use and extend. In this article, we will discuss how to get started with Hugo.
Installing Hugo The first step to getting started with Hugo is to install it. Hugo is available for Windows, Mac, and Linux.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="getting-started-with-hugo">Getting Started with Hugo</h1>
<p>Hugo is a modern static website generator that can help you quickly create a website with a great user experience. It is a fast and powerful open source framework that is easy to use and extend. In this article, we will discuss how to get started with Hugo.</p>
<h2 id="installing-hugo">Installing Hugo</h2>
<p>The first step to getting started with Hugo is to install it. Hugo is available for Windows, Mac, and Linux. You can download the latest version from the <a href="https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/">Hugo website</a>.</p>
<h2 id="creating-a-site">Creating a Site</h2>
<p>Once you have installed Hugo, you can create a new site using the <code>hugo new site</code> command. This will create a new folder with the necessary files and folders for your new site.</p>
<h2 id="adding-content">Adding Content</h2>
<p>Next, you can add content to your site. Hugo uses Markdown files for content. You can create a new Markdown file by running the <code>hugo new &lt;filename&gt;</code> command. This will create a new file with the <code>.md</code> extension in the <code>content</code> folder.</p>
<h2 id="adding-a-theme">Adding a Theme</h2>
<p>You can also add a theme to your site. Hugo provides a number of themes that you can choose from. You can find themes in the <a href="https://themes.gohugo.io/">Hugo Themes</a> directory. To add a theme, you can run the <code>hugo --theme &lt;themename&gt;</code> command.</p>
<h2 id="building-your-site">Building Your Site</h2>
<p>Finally, you can build your site by running the <code>hugo</code> command. This will generate the HTML files for your site and put them in the <code>public</code> folder. You can then upload these files to a web server to make your site live.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s it! You now know how to get started with Hugo.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
